{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This author of Postcards from the Edge wrote multiple autobiographical works that openly discuss her positive experience with electroconvulsive therapy as treatment for bipolar disorder. This author of the memoir The Princess Diarist is, with her mother, the subject of Bright Lights, a documentary that premiered on HBO in January 2017, just weeks after their deaths. For ten points, name this mental health advocate, daughter of Debbie Reynolds, and actress who portrayed Princess Leia in the Star Wars films.",
      "answer": "Carrie Fisher"
    },
    {
      "question": "Oscar L´opez Rivera, an independence activist for this territory, had his prison sentence commuted during Barack Obama’s last week in office. In 2016, this territory was blocked from declaring bankruptcy by the Supreme Court. Like Guam and the Philippines, this commonwealth’s ownership transferred to the U.S. after the Spanish-American War. For ten points, name this Caribbean island territory where activists in its capital, San Juan, wish to become the 51st U.S. state.",
      "answer": "Puerto Rico"
    },
    {
      "question": "These people discovered a “land of stone slabs” that might be the Torngat Mountains. These people harvestedlumberfromMarklandandrecordedfindinggrapesinanotherarea.Thesepeoplebattledagainst Skraelings and found grapes during their brief settlements in Vinland and at L’Anse Aux Meadows. The first European peoples to land in Canada were, for ten points, what Scandinavians, including the explorer Leif Ericsson?",
      "answer": [
        "Norsemen or Vikings",
        "Danes",
        "Greenlanders"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This group regularly held meetings at the Menger Hotel Bar of San Antonio. After the Battle of Las Guasimas, the doctor Leonard Wood ceased to be the leader of this group, which presented a president with a bronze miniature of Remington’s Bronco Buster. In their most famous engagement, this group charged up the Kettle and San Juan Hills in Cuba. For ten points, name this volunteer cavalry unit that was led by Teddy Roosevelt during the Spanish American War.",
      "answer": "Rough Riders or the 1st United States Volunteer Cavalry Regiment, prompting on partial answers thereof"
    },
    {
      "question": "This composer depicted the industrialization of the Soviet Union in his ballet The Steel Step and used music from his unperformed ballet Ala i Lolli to write the Scythian Suite. A work by this composer written for an audience of Young Pioneers uses the clarinet to represent a cat, and this composer included the “Dance of the Knights” in a Shakespearean ballet. For ten points, name this Soviet composer of the ballet Romeo and Juliet and Peter and the Wolf.",
      "answer": "Sergei Sergeyevich Prokofiev"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s policy ran on the ideas of “peace at home, peace in the world,” though his troops almost prompted war with Great Britain in the Chanak crisis. After securing independence, this man was able to replace the Treaty of Sevres with the Treaty of Lausanne. As part of “Six Arrows” ideology, this leader banned the fez. Years after he won at Gallipoli, this leader established a new capital at Ankara. For ten points, name this founder of modern Turkey.",
      "answer": [
        "Mustafa Kemal Ataturk",
        "either underlined portion"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s wounding at the Breymann redoubt is commemorated by the “Boot Monument” in New York. This man was forced to flee on the Vulture after he was implicated by a set of secret plans that were found with John Andre. After Horatio Gates took the credit for this man’s successes at the Battle of Saratoga, this man plotted to surrender West Point to the British. For ten points, name this treasonous American Revolutionary War general.",
      "answer": "Benedict Arnold"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Cutter incident, vaccines of this virus were accidentally tainted with live virus. The inventor of the vaccine for this disease defended his decision to not patent it with the rebuttal “Could you patent the sun?” Wild cases of this disease in 2015 were reported only in Afghanistan and Pakistan. The “iron lung” was primarily used to assist sufferers of, for ten points, what viral disease whose vaccine was developed by Jonas Salk?",
      "answer": "poliomyelitis"
    },
    {
      "question": "This country faced a round of protests when the Cinema Rex fire was mistakenly blamed on government operatives. The Army of Knowledge was established in this country to improve literacy during the White Revolution, which was supported by the repression of the SAVAK police. Shortly after the overthrow of Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, this country fell under the grasp of the Ayatollah Khomeini. For ten points, name this country, the site of a 444-day-long hostage crisis in the American embassy in Tehran.",
      "answer": "Islamic Republic of Iran"
    },
    {
      "question": "A Polish person of uncertain identity who held this profession is dubbed Gallus Anonymous. Aside from being a monk, a resident of Kiev named Nestor was an early practitioner of this profession. The Byzantine Procopius held this profession, producing a “Secret” book that described the misdeeds of Theodora and Justinian. Herodotus is called the father of, for ten points, what profession that involves chronicling the past?",
      "answer": "historian or chronicler"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In 2014, this country lifted its moratorium on the death penalty after over 140 people were killed in an attack on the Army Public School. This country’s national airline was mocked for sacrificing a goat before a flight, in order to fend off bad luck from a December 2016 plane crash that killed 47 people. For 4 months in 2016, this country imposed a ban on Bollywood films. Nawaz Sharif leads, for ten points, what country whose capital is Islamabad?",
        "answer": "Islamic Republic of Pakistan"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The aforementioned Pakistani ban on Bollywood films was a response to increasing violence in the Indian-controlled part of this region, where violence was sparked after police killed Burhan Wani of the Hizbul Mujahedeen.",
        "answer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This case built upon the ruling of Powell v. Alabama, which was unclear in whether certain rights were afforded in non-capital instances. Betts v. Brady was overruled by this case, in which Abe Fortas was assigned to work with the defendant. The accused in this case had broken into a Florida pool hall and, due to his poverty, was forced to represent himself in trial. For ten points, name this 1963 Supreme Court case that established the right to a state-appointed attorney for poor defendants.",
        "answer": [
          "Gideon v. Wainwright",
          "in either order"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The right toan attorney derives from this amendment inthe Bill of Rights, which also guarantees a speedy, public trial.",
        "answer": "6th Amendment"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "When this man took the throne, he killed two of his father’s advisers and his brother Adonijah. This man’s son promised to be harsher to his subjects than this man was, a mistake that led to the division of this man’s kingdom. Earlier, this father of Rehoboam offered a thousand burnt offerings at the Temple he built, for which God gave him wisdom and fabulous wealth. For ten points, name this king of Israel, the son and successor of David.",
        "answer": [
          "Solomon",
          "Shlomo",
          "Jedidiah"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Solomon is traditionally credited as the author of this book of wisdom. Its third chapter begins with a passage noting “For everything there is a season...”",
        "answer": [
          "Ecclesiastes",
          "Kohelet"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The losing side in this battle lost the commander of its vanguard, Jean le Maingre [MAN-gruh]. The losers were able to successfully raid the baggage train of the victor of this battle, but lost their commander Charles d’Albret and were forced to sign the Treaty of Troyes. A cavalry charge during this battle was bogged down by mud and ran into stakes, leading to massive losses of knights. For ten points, name this decisive victory for English longbowmen during the Hundred Years’ War.",
        "answer": "Battle of Agincourt"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Another decisive victory for England in the Hundred Years War was this 1346 victory for Edward III, which allowed him to capture Calais and proved the importance of the longbow.",
        "answer": "Battle of Cr´ecy"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Shortly before this man’s death, he sent an unsuccessful punitive expedition against the Singhasari kingdom of Java. This man was victorious in the Toluid war against his brother, Ariq Boke, though his attempts to conquer Japan were thwarted by the “divine wind,” kamikaze. The Italian explorer Marco Polo visited this ruler’s capital of Dadu, located in modern day Beijing. For ten points, name this founder of the Yuan Dynasty in China and grandson of Genghis Khan.",
        "answer": "Kublai Khan"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Kublai Khan ordered three invasions into this country, led by the Tran dynasty and the Champa, both of which agreed to become Mongol vassals. In the 19th century, the Nguyen dynasty led this Southeast Asian country.",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This play’s line “I will save you tomorrow... from yourself I will save you” is often omitted because its Act 2, Scene 2 is usually not performed. Liam Neeson starred in a 2002 revival of this play, in which a “poppet” is created by Mary Warren. After asking for “more weight,” Giles Corey is crushed to death in this play. John Proctor is hanged at the end of, for ten points, what Red Scare allegory set during the Salem Witch Trials, a play written by Arthur Miller?",
        "answer": "The Crucible"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Another Arthur Miller play, Incident at this location, is set before a World War II interrogation. Philippe Petain was among the leaders of its puppet government.",
        "answer": [
          "Vichy",
          "Incident at Vichy",
          "Vichy France"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This city was attacked after Imre Th¨ok¨oly asked Kara Mustafa for assistance. Matthias Corvinus captured this city during his conflict with Frederick III. This city was attacked at the end of a campaign for Hungary that began after the Battle of Mohacs [moh-hotch]. The intervention of Polish Winged Hussars under Jan Sobieski saved this city in 1683. For ten points, name this city that was besieged twice by the Ottoman Empire as it tried to defeat Austria.",
        "answer": "Vienna"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Vienna became known for these institutions after the 1683 siege, when Turkish soldiers left bags of beans behind. They became known as places of culture and elegance.",
        "answer": [
          "coffee houses",
          "equivalents, including caf´es"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Early knowledge about this event was derived from the journals of Patrick Gass. This event’s only casualty was Charles Floyd, who died of appendicitis in present-day Sioux City. A slave named York and the translator Toussaint Charbonneau aided this journey, which Thomas Jefferson ordered to explore the newly bought Louisiana Territory. Sacagawea aided, for ten points, what American expedition into the Western United States?",
        "answer": "Lewis and Clark Expedition or the Corps of Discovery expedition"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Lewis and Clark Expedition set off from Camp Dubois [doo-bwah] in this state, from which they entered modern-day Missouri. Roughly three decades later, Joseph Smith brought his followers from Missouri to the village of Nauvoo in this state.",
        "answer": "Illinois"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "The U.S. in World War I",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Second-to-last year of the war, in which the U.S. finally joined the fighting?",
          "answer": "1917"
        },
        {
          "question": "Prior American policy of not officially supporting either side, also held by Switzerland.",
          "answer": [
            "neutrality",
            "word forms"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Type of vehicle operated by “Aces” such as Eddie Rickenbacker and the German Red Baron.",
          "answer": [
            "aircraft",
            "airplanes",
            "fighters"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Note sent by Germany proposing an anti-American alliance with Mexico.",
          "answer": "Zimmerman Telegram"
        },
        {
          "question": "Secretary of State who resigned in 1915, years after delivering the “Cross of Gold” speech?",
          "answer": "William Jennings Bryan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Man, nicknamed “Black Jack,” who led the American Expeditionary Force.",
          "answer": "John Pershing"
        },
        {
          "question": "Slang term that described A.E.F. infantrymen and marines and was eventually superseded by “GIs” in World War II.",
          "answer": "Doughboys"
        },
        {
          "question": "Businessman who oversaw the War Industries Board to oversee American military preparedness.",
          "answer": "Bernard Baruch"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "French Revolution",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "French King executed during the Revolution.",
          "answer": "Louis XVI"
        },
        {
          "question": "Parisian prison that was stormed at the beginning of the French Revolution.",
          "answer": "the Bastille Saint-Antoine"
        },
        {
          "question": "Popular, sharp method of execution, which became a symbol of the excessive violence during the Reign of Terror.",
          "answer": [
            "guillotine",
            "word forms"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Revolutionary who started the Reign of Terror, which ended with his execution.",
          "answer": "Maximilien Robespierre"
        },
        {
          "question": "Traditional subdivision of French society that was less powerful than the clergy and nobility.",
          "answer": "Third Estate"
        },
        {
          "question": "Radical journalist and revolutionary who was assassinated by Charlotte Corday in his bath.",
          "answer": "Jean-Paul Marat"
        },
        {
          "question": "Location of a 1789 oath to create a constitution, a pivotal event early in the Revolution.",
          "answer": [
            "a tennis court",
            "the Tennis Court Oath"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Coup against radical Jacobins that put an end to the Reign of Terror.",
          "answer": "Thermidorian Reaction"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Ramesses the Great",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Ancient civilization whose New Kingdom rulers included Ramesses the Great.",
          "answer": "ancient Egypt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Status that Ramesses aspired to achieve. Other beings with this status included Ra and Horus.",
          "answer": [
            "godhood",
            "broad equivalents relating to divinity"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Military vehicles that Ramesses used, consisting of a carriage pulled by horses.",
          "answer": "chariots"
        },
        {
          "question": "1274 BC battle that Ramesses fought against the Hittites, the largest battle of those vehicles in history.",
          "answer": "Battle of Kadesh"
        },
        {
          "question": "Diplomatic agreement made between Ramesses and Hattusili III, the first recorded example in history.",
          "answer": "peace treaty"
        },
        {
          "question": "Site of Ramesses’s tomb, located near Thebes. The tomb of Tutankhamun was also located here.",
          "answer": "Valley of the Kings"
        },
        {
          "question": "Wife of Ramesses, for whom he constructed a temple at Abu Simbel.",
          "answer": "Nefertari"
        },
        {
          "question": "Region to the south, home to the kingdoms of Kush and Mero¨e, that Ramesses attacked.",
          "answer": "Nubia"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The busiest cantilever bridge in the world connects this city to Howrah. This city’s former Dalhousie Square was renamed B. B. D. Bagh after independence. Located on the Hooghly River, a Home for the Dying was established here by the Missionaries of Charity, led by an (20 pts)",
        "Albanian-born nun. This city’s Fort William was the site of a 1756 incident where British prisoners were suffocated in a small room. A (10 pts)",
        "“Black Hole” tragedy took place in, for ten points, what Indian city in the Ganges Delta, the capital of West Bengal and adopted home of Mother Teresa?"
      ],
      "answer": "Kolkata or Calcutta"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) To prevent this country from surrendering, the son of its leader was kidnapped in Operation Panzerfaust by Otto Skorzeny. The two Vienna Awards returned territory that this country had lost in the Treaty of (20 pts)",
        "Trianon. Ferenc Sz´alasi [fer-entz sh-lah-zee] replaced Admiral Mikl´os Horthy as leader of this country, allowing the Arrow Cross Party to take power, and J´anos K´ad´ar [yan-osh kah-dar] took power in this country after it attempted to leave the (10 pts)",
        "Warsaw Pact. For ten points, name this country where Imre Nagy’s [nahj’s] 1956 revolution was crushed by Soviet tanks in Budapest."
      ],
      "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One block of this city’s Camac Street is paved with wooden blocks. A house on Osage Avenue in this city’s Cobbs Creek section was bombed by the city’s own police force. The (20 pts)",
        "1981 MOVE bombing took place in this city, whose original plan called for five squares, one of which was converted to Logan Circle. A building on this city’s Chestnut Street was the main (10 pts)",
        "meeting place for the Second Continental Congress. The Benjamin Franklin Parkway runs through, for ten points, what city, founded by William Penn and home to Independence Hall?"
      ],
      "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) These people were targeted in the Weenen massacre. They established the state of Natalia after recovering a lost treaty from the body of their leader, Piet Retief, who had been executed by (20 pts)",
        "Dingaan. Andries Pretorius led these people to victory at the Blood River by utilizing a laager fort against (10 pts)",
        "Zulus seeking to disrupt the Great Trek. These people founded the Orange Free State after leaving the British-held Cape Colony. For ten points, name these Dutch-speaking people of South Africa."
      ],
      "answer": "Boers"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This subject of one of this artist’s paintings wears a medallion given to him by Alexander the Great while resting his hand on a bust of an ancient poet. This artist’s numerous self-portraits include one etching with his wife, (20 pts)",
        "Saskia. He included a young girl in a yellow dress with a chicken hanging from her belt in his portrait of arquebusiers under the command of (10 pts)",
        "Frans Banning Cocq. For ten points, name this Dutch artist of The Anatomy Lesson of Dr. Nicolaes Tulp and The Night Watch."
      ],
      "answer": "Rembrandt van Rijn"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A contingency plan to defend this structure was drawn up in Operation Sand Flea. A French attempt to build this structure failed when Ferdinand de (20 pts)",
        "Lesseps was found to be misappropriating funds. The Darien Scheme tried to build this strcuture, whose construction began in earnest after the (10 pts)",
        "Hay-Bunau-Varilla treaty. This structure was returned to the government of Omar Torrijos by Jimmy Carter in 1977. For ten points, name this Central American waterway that links the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans."
      ],
      "answer": "Panama Canal"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Catherine Cheynel foiled a surprise attack on this city by Charles Emmanuel I of Savoy by pouring soup on the attackers, which is commemorated in l’Escalade. Jean-Henri Dunant founded an organization in this city after the Battle of (20 pts)",
        "Solferino, and a treaty signed in this city defines the term “refugee.” The Hague Conventions updated a series of treaties signed in this city, home to the International (10 pts)",
        "Red Cross. For ten points, name this Swiss city, which names conventions concerning treatment of prisoners of war and non-combatants."
      ],
      "answer": "Geneva"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This city suffered the “Night of the Black Snow” in 1945. The 20th Air Force frequently attacked this city in Operation Matterhorn. Operation (20 pts)",
        "Meetinghouse, which targeted this city for firebombing, was the deadliest single air raid during World War II. A park in (10 pts)",
        "Yokoamicho Park commemorates victims of air raids in this city, where the International Military Tribunal for the Far East was held. For ten points, name this Japanese city and capital during World War II."
      ],
      "answer": "Tokyo"
    }
  ]
}